# Aksanti BAHIGA Tacite

Bukavu, South Kivu, Democratic Republic of the Congo

tacite.bahiga@gmail.com

+243999537410

linkedin.com/in/aksantibahiga

# **Summary**

Medium front-end developer with 4 years of experience designing and building responsive web apps. Proficient with CSS, SCSS, and JS Frameworks, with extensive knowledge of UX and UI design. Adept at contributing to a highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions, and determining customer satisfaction.

## **Experience**



## Frontend Developer

Chow Al

Dec 2022 - Present (1 year 4 months)

Chowai, an AI platform that generates African recipes. My primary responsibility is to develop and maintain the user interface of the application using React and NextJS.

#### **Content Creator**

**Drcmind** 

Jul 2022 - Present (1 year 9 months)

- Content creator (web dev courses)
- Bringing UI to life using react and other frontend libraries

#### Frontend Developer

**HNG Internship** 

Oct 2022 - Dec 2022 (3 months)

- Working in a team of +20 web developers for creating real-world application
- Used React with styled-components for creating amazing design (styles)
- Bringing to life UI designs
- integrating API in react app,
- Writing test with Jest
- Contributing to an open-source project (Zuri chat)

#### **Education**

### Université catholique de Bukavu

Licence, Ingénierie informatique Dec 2020 - Dec 2023

# École d'application

High School Diploma, Commercial et 2014 - 2020

## **Licenses & Certifications**

Jeune blogueur UNICEF - UNICEF

CSS complete course for beginners - Udemy UC-49b60632-f98b-4927-8089-75faa149ee2d

CSS and JavaScript crash course - Udemy UC-0e010530-33cb-47b2-b8ef-a3cf8f3039cf

JavaScript for beginners, the complete introduction to JS - Udemy UC-0df32ac0-ea5f-4b0d-9d9e-edea3dd1f122

## **Skills**

Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • Next.js • npm • Chart.js • Leadership • Front-End Development • Teamwork • Node.js • Test Driven Development • GitHub